<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Academic on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/tags/academic/</link><description>Recent content in Academic on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 12:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dicksonneoh.com/tags/academic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Celebrating a Milestone in the Top 2% of Global Scientists</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/world_top_scientist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/world_top_scientist/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to tell you that I&amp;rsquo;m one of the top 2% of scientists in the world for 2023, according to Stanford University. It&amp;rsquo;s been ten years of hard work in research and learning, and this award means a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="-the-journey">ðŸ›¤ï¸ The Journey&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When I started, it was easy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had been in academic for some time as a student and research assistant. And I had the resources, for a good start. I thought it&amp;rsquo;s too good to be true. But reality hits mid journey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Academia to Industry: Insights from an AI/ML Engineer</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/podcast_ai_ml_data_talks_episode_fifteen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/podcast_ai_ml_data_talks_episode_fifteen/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="-aiml-data-talks-podcast">ðŸ’« AI/ML Data Talks Podcast&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this podcast episode I share about my journey and transition from academia to industry and the lessons I learned along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During our chat, we talk about some of the hottest topics in machine learning, like What is MLOps? Data Drift vs Concept Drift, and Monitoring Machine Learning Model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also talked about some insights into the latest AI and ML trends and ecosystem. Specifically how important it is for various tools to be able to communicate with each other, and how &lt;a href="https://zenml.io/home" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">ZenML&lt;/a> helps with that.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>