<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>object-classification on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/categories/object-classification/</link><description>Recent content in object-classification on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 11:00:15 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dicksonneoh.com/categories/object-classification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fastdup: A Powerful Tool to Manage, Clean &amp; Curate Visual Data at Scale on Your CPU - For Free.</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/fastdup_manage_clean_curate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 11:00:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/fastdup_manage_clean_curate/</guid><description>✅ Motivation As a data scientist, you might be tempted to jump into modeling as soon as you can. I mean, that&amp;rsquo;s the fun part, right?
But trust me, if you skip straight to modeling without taking the time to really understand the problem and analyze the data, you&amp;rsquo;re setting yourself up for failure.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been there.
You might feel like a superstar, but you&amp;rsquo;ll have with a model that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work 🤦‍♂️.</description></item><item><title>TIMM at the Edge: Deploying Over 964 PyTorch Image Models on Android with TorchScript and Flutter</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/timm_torchscript_flutter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 11:00:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/timm_torchscript_flutter/</guid><description>info
This blog post is still a work in progress. If you require further clarifications before the contents are finalized, please get in touch with me here, on LinkedIn, or Twitter. 🔥 Motivation You finally got into a Kaggle competition. You found a getting-started notebook written by a Kaggle Grandmaster and immediately trained a state-of-the-art (SOTA) image classification model.
After some fiddling, you found yourself in the leaderboard topping the charts with 99.</description></item></channel></rss>