<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IceVision on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/tags/icevision/</link><description>Recent content in IceVision on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:07:15 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dicksonneoh.com/tags/icevision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Training a Deep Learning Model for Cell Counting in 17 Lines of Code with 17 Images</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/training_dl_model_for_cell_counting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:07:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/training_dl_model_for_cell_counting/</guid><description>🕶️ Motivation Numerous biology and medical procedures involve counting cells from images taken with a microscope. Counting cells reveals the concentration of bacteria and viruses and gives vital information on the progress of a disease. To accomplish the counting, researchers painstakingly count the cells by hand with the assistance of a device called hemocytometer. This process is repetitive, tedious, and prone to errors.
What if we could automate the counting by using an intelligent deep learning algorithm instead?</description></item><item><title>Contributing to open-source: Lessons learned</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/contributing_to_open_source_lessons_learned/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/contributing_to_open_source_lessons_learned/</guid><description>☀️ Introduction I was recently given the recognition by the folks at IceVision to be part of the core-developer team! Farid Hassainia, a co-creator of the IceVision Tweeted about it on March 17, 2022. We are super excited to introduce you to our 🎉New Core-Dev: Dickson Neoh @dicksonneoh7
Dickson is actively contributing to IceVision. He ardently helps IceVision users in our Discord Community.
We are very happy to have him on our team!</description></item><item><title>Deploy IceVision Models on HuggingFace Spaces</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/deploy_icevision_models_on_huggingface_spaces/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 13:42:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/deploy_icevision_models_on_huggingface_spaces/</guid><description>Introduction So, you’ve trained a deep learning model that can detect objects from images. Next, how can you share the awesomeness of your model with the rest of the world? You might be a PhD student trying to get some ideas from your peers or supervisors, or a startup founder who wishes to share a minimum viable product to your clients for feedback. But, at the same time you don&amp;rsquo;t wish to go through the hassle of dealing with MLOps.</description></item></channel></rss>