<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 20:48:15 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I Made It to GitHub Trending - My Open Source Journey</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/i_made_it_github_trending/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/i_made_it_github_trending/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="-introduction">ðŸ‘‹ Introduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>On October 28th, 2024 I made it to GitHub Trending! This wasn&amp;rsquo;t something I expected to happen, and I&amp;rsquo;m still in disbelief.&lt;/p>




 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;figure style="text-align: center;">
 &lt;a href="https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/i_made_it_github_trending/trending_developer.png" class="image-popup">
 &lt;img src="https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/i_made_it_github_trending/trending_developer.png"
 alt="GitHub Trending Developer for 28th October 2024" 
 width="auto" 
 
 style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"/>
 &lt;/a>
 
 &lt;figcaption style="font-size: 0.8em;">
 &lt;p>
 GitHub Trending Developer for 28th October 2024
 
 
 
 &lt;/p> 
 &lt;/figcaption>
 
 &lt;/figure>
 

&lt;p>But after all the dopamine rush, I&amp;rsquo;m back to reality and I want to share my journey on how I made it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is mostly a note to myself and I hope it can help you too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Celebrating a Milestone in the Top 2% of Global Scientists</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/world_top_scientist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/world_top_scientist/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to tell you that I&amp;rsquo;m one of the top 2% of scientists in the world for 2023, according to Stanford University. It&amp;rsquo;s been ten years of hard work in research and learning, and this award means a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="-the-journey">ðŸ›¤ï¸ The Journey&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When I started, it was easy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had been in academic for some time as a student and research assistant. And I had the resources, for a good start. I thought it&amp;rsquo;s too good to be true. But reality hits mid journey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Academia to Industry: Insights from an AI/ML Engineer</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/podcast_ai_ml_data_talks_episode_fifteen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/podcast_ai_ml_data_talks_episode_fifteen/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="-aiml-data-talks-podcast">ðŸ’« AI/ML Data Talks Podcast&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this podcast episode I share about my journey and transition from academia to industry and the lessons I learned along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During our chat, we talk about some of the hottest topics in machine learning, like What is MLOps? Data Drift vs Concept Drift, and Monitoring Machine Learning Model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also talked about some insights into the latest AI and ML trends and ecosystem. Specifically how important it is for various tools to be able to communicate with each other, and how &lt;a href="https://zenml.io/home" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">ZenML&lt;/a> helps with that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Applications of Edge AI with Sage Elliot at Whylabs</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_rsqrd_applications_edge_ai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_rsqrd_applications_edge_ai/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="-introduction">âœ¨ Introduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Running AI on the Edge has become a widely discussed topic in the world of artificial intelligence. At its core, the concept of Edge AI involves putting AI algorithms as close to the user or data as possible. This is in contrast to the traditional server-based approach, where computations are carried out in remote servers, leading to slow response times and the need to transfer data back and forth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ML Pipelines from the Get Go (Without Tears)</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_ml_pipelines_from_the_get_go/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_ml_pipelines_from_the_get_go/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="-takeaways">ðŸ’« Takeaways&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this talk, I discussed why ML pipelines should be built from the get-go. Here are some of the key takeaways:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1ï¸âƒ£ Despite the hype around machine learning, 55% of companies have not deployed a single ML model yet, and those who have are struggling to maintain and scale them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2ï¸âƒ£ Putting ML in production is not just about ML, but also about engineering. Many companies are doing more engineering than ML to solve various issues that arise in the pipeline.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cool Data Projects Show with Kristen - Gun Detection on CPU</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_cool_data_science_cpu_pistol_detection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_cool_data_science_cpu_pistol_detection/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="-introduction">ðŸ”¥ Introduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The rapid advancement in computer vision technology has led to the development of sophisticated models that can perform complex tasks, such as object detection and segmentation, with high accuracy. However, these models often require high computational resources and can be slow when running on a CPU. This can pose a challenge for real-time applications, such as surveillance and security, where quick detection and analysis of objects is critical.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leveraging Open Source Tools to Deploy Models (Without ðŸ˜¥)</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_tfdl_deploying_dl_without_tears/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_tfdl_deploying_dl_without_tears/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="-introduction">ðŸ’¡ Introduction&lt;/h3>




 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;figure>
 &lt;a href="https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_tfdl_deploying_dl_without_tears/aboutme.png" class="image-popup">
 &lt;img src="https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_tfdl_deploying_dl_without_tears/aboutme.png"
 
 
 
 style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"/>
 &lt;/a>
 
 &lt;/figure>
 

&lt;p>This talk was given to the Tensorflow Deep Learning Malaysia Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/TensorFlowMY/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">group&lt;/a> during the June 2022 online meetup.
The group had over 7.5k members consisting of audience from various background related to artificial intelligence in Malaysia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal of the talk is to introduce the members to existing open-source tools they can use to deploy models on the cloud and edge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Half of the audience has no experience with deep learning.
Hence, the talk was tailored to beginners in the field.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contributing to open-source: Lessons learned</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/contributing_to_open_source_lessons_learned/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/contributing_to_open_source_lessons_learned/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="-introduction">â˜€ï¸ Introduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I was recently given the recognition by the folks at &lt;a href="https://github.com/airctic/icevision" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">IceVision&lt;/a> to be part of the core-developer team!
&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/farid-hassainia-ca/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Farid Hassainia&lt;/a>, a co-creator of the IceVision Tweeted about it on March 17, 2022.
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet">&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">We are super excited to introduce you to our ðŸŽ‰New Core-Dev: Dickson Neoh &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dicksonneoh7?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@dicksonneoh7&lt;/a>&lt;br>&lt;br>Dickson is actively contributing to IceVision. He ardently helps IceVision users in our Discord Community.&lt;br>&lt;br>We are very happy to have him on our team! &lt;a href="https://t.co/SO1qLHkarm">pic.twitter.com/SO1qLHkarm&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Digital Logic Design - Course</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/course_digital_logic_design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/course_digital_logic_design/</guid><description>&lt;p>A collection of recorded lecture classes for the Digital Logic Design course I taught at National Energy University, Malaysia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>View the playlist &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLqGyAx3n9NxriN8V6ar-x-GFnkAtkTL1n" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>