<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recents Article on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Recents Article on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 20:48:15 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Contributing to open-source: Lessons learned</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/contributing_to_open_source_lessons_learned/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/contributing_to_open_source_lessons_learned/</guid><description>Introduction I was recently given the recognition by the folks at IceVision to be part of the core-developer team! Farid Hassainia, a co-creator of the IceVision Tweeted about it on March 17, 2022. We are super excited to introduce you to our 🎉New Core-Dev: Dickson Neoh @dicksonneoh7
Dickson is actively contributing to IceVision. He ardently helps IceVision users in our Discord Community.
We are very happy to have him on our team!</description></item><item><title>Deep Learning on Android with Flutter and Hugging Face</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/deep_learning_on_android_with_flutter_and_hugging_face/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 15:07:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/deep_learning_on_android_with_flutter_and_hugging_face/</guid><description>Motivation Numerous biology and medical procedure involve counting cells from images taken with microscope. Counting cells reveals the concentration of bacteria and viruses and gives vital information on the progress of a disease. To accomplish the counting, a device known as the hemocytometer or a counting chamber is used. The hemocytometer creates volumetric grid to divide each region on the image for accurate counting. The following image shows an image taken from a hemocytometer.</description></item><item><title>Deploy IceVision Models on HuggingFace Spaces</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/deploy_icevision_models_on_huggingface_spaces/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 13:42:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/deploy_icevision_models_on_huggingface_spaces/</guid><description>Introduction So, you’ve trained a deep learning model that can detect objects from images. Next, how can you share the awesomeness of your model with the rest of the world? You might be a PhD student trying to get some ideas from your peers or supervisors, or a startup founder who wishes to share a minimum viable product to your clients for feedback. But, at the same time you don&amp;rsquo;t wish to go through the hassle of dealing with MLOps.</description></item></channel></rss>