<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hugging Face on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/tags/hugging-face/</link><description>Recent content in Hugging Face on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 11:00:15 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dicksonneoh.com/tags/hugging-face/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying GPT-J Models on a Telegram Bot with Hugging Face Hub - For Free</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/deploy_gpt_hf_models_on_telegram/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 11:00:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/deploy_gpt_hf_models_on_telegram/</guid><description>💥 Motivation tip
By the end of this post you will learn how to:
Set up a Telegram bot with a Python wrapper library. Use the Gradio API to access the GPT-J model prediction. Host the Telegram bot on Hugging Face Spaces. By the end of this post, you&amp;rsquo;ll have your own Telegram bot that has access to the GPT-J-6B model. All for free.
Deploying a state-of-the-art (SOTA) GPT-like language model on a chatbot can be tricky.</description></item><item><title>How to Deploy Object Detection Models on Android with Flutter</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/how_to_deploy_od_models_on_android_with_flutter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 15:00:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/how_to_deploy_od_models_on_android_with_flutter/</guid><description>🚑 Deployment: Where ML models go to die In this post, I will outline the basic steps to deploy ML models onto lightweight mobile devices easily, quickly and for free.
tip
By the end of this post, you will learn about:
Leveraging Hugging Face infrastructure to host models. Deploying on any edge device using REST API. Displaying the results on a Flutter Android app. According to Gartner, more than 85% of machine learning (ML) models never made it into production.</description></item><item><title>Bringing High-Quality Image Models to Mobile: Hugging Face TIMM Meets Android &amp; iOS</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/bringing_high_quality_image_models_to_mobile/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 11:00:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/bringing_high_quality_image_models_to_mobile/</guid><description>info
This blog post is still a work in progress. If you require further clarifications before the contents are finalized, please get in touch with me here, on LinkedIn, or Twitter. 🌟 Motivation For many data scientist (including myself), we pride ourselves in training a model, seeing the loss graph go down, and claim victory when the test set accuracy reaches 99.99235%.
Why not?
This is the after all the juiciest part of the job.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Object Detection Models on Hugging Face Spaces</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/deploy_icevision_models_on_huggingface_spaces/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 13:42:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/deploy_icevision_models_on_huggingface_spaces/</guid><description>Introduction So, you’ve trained a deep learning model that can detect objects from images. Next, how can you share the awesomeness of your model with the rest of the world? You might be a PhD student trying to get some ideas from your peers or supervisors, or a startup founder who wishes to share a minimum viable product to your clients for feedback. But, at the same time you don&amp;rsquo;t wish to go through the hassle of dealing with MLOps.</description></item></channel></rss>