<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/</link><description>Recent content on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 15:07:15 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Training a Deep Learning Model for Cell Counting in 17 Lines of Code with 17 Images</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/training_dl_model_for_cell_counting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 15:07:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/training_dl_model_for_cell_counting/</guid><description>🕶️ Motivation Numerous biology and medical procedures involve counting cells from images taken with microscope. Counting cells reveals the concentration of bacteria and viruses and gives vital information on the progress of a disease. To accomplish the counting, researchers painstakingly count the cells by hand with the assistance of a device called hemocytometer. This process is repetitive, tedious, and prone to errors.
What if we could automate the counting by using an intelligent deep learning algorithm instead?</description></item><item><title>Real-time Vehicle and License Plate Detection with Tensorflow and OpenVINO</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/realtime_vehicle_and_license_plate_detection_with_openvino/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 15:07:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/realtime_vehicle_and_license_plate_detection_with_openvino/</guid><description>Motivation In this work we showcase a real-time vehicle and license plate detection using
Tensorflow Object Detection API Model trained with TFOD API
Intel OpenVINO Framework Model optimized for deployment with OpenVINO
Neural Compute Stick Model deployed on NCS2</description></item><item><title>MicroSense - A Deep Learning Android App for Cell Counting</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/microsense_a_deep_learning_powered_cell_counting_app_with_flutter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 15:07:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/microsense_a_deep_learning_powered_cell_counting_app_with_flutter/</guid><description>Motivation Numerous biology and medical procedure involve counting cells from images taken with microscope. Counting cells reveals the concentration of bacteria and viruses and gives vital information on the progress of a disease. To accomplish the counting, a device known as the hemocytometer or a counting chamber is used. The hemocytometer creates volumetric grid to divide each region on the image for accurate counting. The following image shows an image taken from a hemocytometer.</description></item></channel></rss>