<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>invited-talks on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/categories/invited-talks/</link><description>Recent content in invited-talks on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 20:48:15 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dicksonneoh.com/categories/invited-talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AI/ML Data Talks Podcast Episode 15</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/podcast_ai_ml_data_talks_episode_fifteen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/podcast_ai_ml_data_talks_episode_fifteen/</guid><description>In this episode of the AI/ML talk I talked about some of the hottest topics in machine learning including What is MLOps? Data Drift vs Concept Drift and Monitoring Machine Learning Model.
MLOps (Machine Learning Operations) is a set of practices for managing the lifecycle of machine learning models in production. It involves collaboration between data scientists, software engineers, and IT operations teams to automate and streamline the process of developing, deploying, and maintaining machine learning models.</description></item><item><title>Applications of Edge AI with Sage Elliot at Whylabs</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_rsqrd_applications_edge_ai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_rsqrd_applications_edge_ai/</guid><description>✨ Introduction Running AI on the Edge has become a widely discussed topic in the world of artificial intelligence. At its core, the concept of Edge AI involves putting AI algorithms as close to the user or data as possible. This is in contrast to the traditional server-based approach, where computations are carried out in remote servers, leading to slow response times and the need to transfer data back and forth.</description></item><item><title>ML Pipelines from the Get Go (Without Tears)</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_ml_pipelines_from_the_get_go/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_ml_pipelines_from_the_get_go/</guid><description>In this talk, I discuss one of the most important aspect of putting ML model into production - building a pipeline and why you should do it from the start.
The talk was hosted with FuzzyLabs and Skillsmatter. View the talk on Skillsmatter webpage here.</description></item><item><title>Cool Data Projects Show with Kristen - Gun Detection on CPU</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_cool_data_science_cpu_pistol_detection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_cool_data_science_cpu_pistol_detection/</guid><description>🔥 Introduction The rapid advancement in computer vision technology has led to the development of sophisticated models that can perform complex tasks, such as object detection and segmentation, with high accuracy. However, these models often require high computational resources and can be slow when running on a CPU. This can pose a challenge for real-time applications, such as surveillance and security, where quick detection and analysis of objects is critical.</description></item><item><title>Leveraging Open Source Tools to Deploy Models (Without 😥)</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_tfdl_deploying_dl_without_tears/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 20:48:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/blog/talk_tfdl_deploying_dl_without_tears/</guid><description>💡 Introduction This talk was given to the Tensorflow Deep Learning Malaysia Facebook group during the June 2022 online meetup. The group had over 7.5k members consisting of audience from various background related to artificial intelligence in Malaysia.
The goal of the talk is to introduce the members to existing open-source tools they can use to deploy models on the cloud and edge.
Half of the audience has no experience with deep learning.</description></item></channel></rss>