<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 09:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge Your PyTorch Image Models: Bag of Tricks to 8x Faster Inference with ONNX Runtime &amp; Optimizations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/supercharge_your_pytorch_image_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 09:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/supercharge_your_pytorch_image_models/</guid>
      <description>🚀 Motivation Having real time inference is crucial for many computer vision models. In some applications, a second delay in inference could mean life or death.&#xA;Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re behind the wheels of a self-driving car and the car takes one full second to detect an oncoming truck. Just one second too late, and you could end up in the clouds 👼👼👼&#xA;Or if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky, on the ground.&#xA;I hope that shows you how crucial this problem is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bringing High-Quality Image Models to Mobile: Hugging Face TIMM Meets Android &amp; iOS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/bringing_high_quality_image_models_to_mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 11:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/bringing_high_quality_image_models_to_mobile/</guid>
      <description>🌟 Motivation For many data scientist (including myself), we pride ourselves in training a model, seeing the loss graph go down, and claim victory when the test set accuracy reaches 99.99235%.&#xA;Why not?&#xA;This is the after all the juiciest part of the job. &amp;ldquo;Solving&amp;rdquo; one dataset after another, it may seem like anything around you can be conquered with a simple model.fit.&#xA;That was me two years ago.&#xA;The naive version of me thought that was all about it with machine learning (ML).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PyTorch at the Edge: Deploying Over 964 TIMM Models on Android with TorchScript and Flutter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/pytorch_at_the_edge_timm_torchscript_flutter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 11:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/pytorch_at_the_edge_timm_torchscript_flutter/</guid>
      <description>🔥 Motivation With various high-level libraries like Keras, Transformer, and Fastai, the barrier to training SOTA models has never been lower.&#xA;On top of that with platforms like Google Colab and Kaggle, pretty much anyone can train a reasonably good model using an old laptop or even a mobile phone (with some patience).&#xA;The question is no longer &amp;ldquo;can we train a SOTA model?&amp;rdquo;, but &amp;ldquo;what happens after that?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Unfortunately, after getting the model trained, most people wash their hands off at this point claiming their model works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>fastdup: A Powerful Tool to Manage, Clean &amp; Curate Visual Data at Scale on Your CPU - For Free.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/fastdup_manage_clean_curate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 11:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/fastdup_manage_clean_curate/</guid>
      <description>⏳ Last Updated: March 27, 2023.&#xA;✅ Motivation As a data scientist, you might be tempted to jump into modeling as soon as you can. I mean, that&amp;rsquo;s the fun part, right?&#xA;But trust me, if you skip straight to modeling without taking the time to really understand the problem and analyze the data, you&amp;rsquo;re setting yourself up for failure.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve been there.&#xA;You might feel like a superstar, but you&amp;rsquo;ll have with a model that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work 🤦‍♂️.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supercharging YOLOv5: How I Got 182.4 FPS Inference Without a GPU</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/supercharging_yolov5_180_fps_cpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 11:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/supercharging_yolov5_180_fps_cpu/</guid>
      <description>🔥 Motivation After months of searching, you&amp;rsquo;ve finally found the one.&#xA;The one object detection library that just works. No installation hassle, no package version mismatch, and no CUDA errors.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m talking about the amazingly engineered YOLOv5 object detection library by Ultralytics.&#xA;Elated, you quickly find an interesting dataset from Roboflow and finally trained a state-of-the-art (SOTA) YOLOv5 model to detect firearms from image streams.&#xA;You ran through a quick checklist &amp;ndash;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying GPT-J Models on a Telegram Bot with Hugging Face Hub - For Free</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/deploy_gpt_hf_models_on_telegram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 11:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/deploy_gpt_hf_models_on_telegram/</guid>
      <description>💥 Motivation tip&#xA;By the end of this post you will learn how to:&#xA;Set up a Telegram bot with a Python wrapper library. Use the Gradio API to access the GPT-J model prediction. Host the Telegram bot on Hugging Face Spaces. By the end of this post, you&amp;rsquo;ll have your own Telegram bot that has access to the GPT-J-6B model. All for free.&#xA;Deploying a state-of-the-art (SOTA) GPT-like language model on a chatbot can be tricky.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Squeezing the Best Performance Out of YOLOX with Weights and Biases</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/comparing_yolox_models_weights_and_biases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 11:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/comparing_yolox_models_weights_and_biases/</guid>
      <description>🔎 Motivation tip&#xA;By the end of this post you will learn how to:&#xA;Install the Weights and Biases client and log the YOLOX training metrics. Compare training metrics on Weights and Biases dashboard. Picking the best model with mAP and FPS values. &amp;ldquo;So many models, so little time!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;As a machine learning engineer, I often hear this phrase thrown around in many variations.&#xA;In object detection alone, there are already several hundreds of models out there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faster than GPU: How to 10x your Object Detection Model and Deploy on CPU at 50&#43; FPS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/how_to_10x_your_od_model_and_deploy_50fps_cpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 15:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/how_to_10x_your_od_model_and_deploy_50fps_cpu/</guid>
      <description>🚦 Motivation tip&#xA;By the end of this post, you will learn how to:&#xA;Train state-of-the-art YOLOX model with your own data. Convert the YOLOX PyTorch model into ONNX and OpenVINO IR format. Run quantization algorithm to 10x your model&amp;rsquo;s inference speed. P/S: The final model runs faster on the CPU than the GPU! 😱&#xA;Deep learning (DL), seems to be the magic word that makes anything mundane cool again. We find them everywhere - in news reports, blog posts, articles, research papers, advertisements, and even baby books.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Deploy Object Detection Models on Android with Flutter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/how_to_deploy_od_models_on_android_with_flutter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 15:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/how_to_deploy_od_models_on_android_with_flutter/</guid>
      <description>🚑 Deployment: Where ML models go to die In this post, I will outline the basic steps to deploy ML models onto lightweight mobile devices easily, quickly and for free.&#xA;tip&#xA;By the end of this post, you will learn about:&#xA;Leveraging Hugging Face infrastructure to host models. Deploying on any edge device using REST API. Displaying the results on a Flutter Android app. According to Gartner, more than 85% of machine learning (ML) models never made it into production.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training a Deep Learning Model for Cell Counting in 17 Lines of Code with 17 Images</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/training_dl_model_for_cell_counting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:07:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/training_dl_model_for_cell_counting/</guid>
      <description>🕶️ Motivation Many biology and medical procedures involve counting cells from images taken with a microscope. Counting cells reveals the concentration of bacteria and viruses and gives vital information on the progress of a disease.&#xA;To accomplish the counting, researchers painstakingly count the cells by hand with the assistance of a device called hemocytometer. This process is repetitive, tedious, and prone to errors.&#xA;What if we could automate the counting by using an intelligent deep learning algorithm instead?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Object Detection Models on Hugging Face Spaces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/deploy_icevision_models_on_huggingface_spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 13:42:56 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/deploy_icevision_models_on_huggingface_spaces/</guid>
      <description>Introduction So, you’ve trained a deep learning model that can detect objects from images. Next, how can you share the awesomeness of your model with the rest of the world? You might be a PhD student trying to get some ideas from your peers or supervisors, or a startup founder who wishes to share a minimum viable product to your clients for feedback. But, at the same time you don&amp;rsquo;t wish to go through the hassle of dealing with MLOps.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
