<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modeling on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:44903/categories/modeling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Modeling on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 11:00:15 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:44903/categories/modeling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Supercharging YOLOv5: How I Got 182.4 FPS Inference Without a GPU</title>
      <link>http://localhost:44903/portfolio/supercharging_yolov5_180_fps_cpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 11:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:44903/portfolio/supercharging_yolov5_180_fps_cpu/</guid>
      <description>🔥 Motivation After months of searching, you&amp;rsquo;ve finally found the one.&#xA;The one object detection library that just works. No installation hassle, no package version mismatch, and no CUDA errors.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m talking about the amazingly engineered YOLOv5 object detection library by Ultralytics.&#xA;Elated, you quickly find an interesting dataset from Roboflow and finally trained a state-of-the-art (SOTA) YOLOv5 model to detect firearms from image streams.&#xA;You ran through a quick checklist &amp;ndash;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faster than GPU: How to 10x your Object Detection Model and Deploy on CPU at 50&#43; FPS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:44903/portfolio/how_to_10x_your_od_model_and_deploy_50fps_cpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 15:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:44903/portfolio/how_to_10x_your_od_model_and_deploy_50fps_cpu/</guid>
      <description>🚦 Motivation tip&#xA;By the end of this post, you will learn how to:&#xA;Train state-of-the-art YOLOX model with your own data. Convert the YOLOX PyTorch model into ONNX and OpenVINO IR format. Run quantization algorithm to 10x your model&amp;rsquo;s inference speed. P/S: The final model runs faster on the CPU than the GPU! 😱&#xA;Deep learning (DL), seems to be the magic word that makes anything mundane cool again. We find them everywhere - in news reports, blog posts, articles, research papers, advertisements, and even baby books.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training a Deep Learning Model for Cell Counting in 17 Lines of Code with 17 Images</title>
      <link>http://localhost:44903/portfolio/training_dl_model_for_cell_counting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:07:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:44903/portfolio/training_dl_model_for_cell_counting/</guid>
      <description>🕶️ Motivation Many biology and medical procedures involve counting cells from images taken with a microscope. Counting cells reveals the concentration of bacteria and viruses and gives vital information on the progress of a disease.&#xA;To accomplish the counting, researchers painstakingly count the cells by hand with the assistance of a device called hemocytometer. This process is repetitive, tedious, and prone to errors.&#xA;What if we could automate the counting by using an intelligent deep learning algorithm instead?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
