<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Flutter on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/tags/flutter/</link><description>Recent content in Flutter on Dickson Neoh - Personal Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 11:00:15 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dicksonneoh.com/tags/flutter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PyTorch at the Edge: Deploying Over 964 TIMM Models on Android with TorchScript and Flutter</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/timm_torchscript_flutter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 11:00:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/timm_torchscript_flutter/</guid><description>info
This blog post is still a work in progress. If you require further clarifications before the contents are finalized, please get in touch with me here, on LinkedIn, or Twitter. 🔥 Motivation You finally got into a Kaggle competition. You found a getting-started notebook written by a Kaggle Grandmaster and immediately trained a state-of-the-art (SOTA) image classification model.
After some fiddling, you found yourself in the leaderboard topping the charts with 99.</description></item><item><title>How to Deploy Object Detection Models on Android with Flutter</title><link>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/how_to_deploy_od_models_on_android_with_flutter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 15:00:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://dicksonneoh.com/portfolio/how_to_deploy_od_models_on_android_with_flutter/</guid><description>🚑 Deployment: Where ML models go to die In this post, I will outline the basic steps to deploy ML models onto lightweight mobile devices easily, quickly and for free.
tip
By the end of this post, you will learn about:
Leveraging Hugging Face infrastructure to host models. Deploying on any edge device using REST API. Displaying the results on a Flutter Android app. According to Gartner, more than 85% of machine learning (ML) models never made it into production.</description></item></channel></rss>